<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eml:eml packageId="knb-lter-jrn.210086002.96"
  system="https://pasta.edirepository.org"
  xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0"
  xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.2"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd">
  <access
    authSystem="https://pasta.edirepository.org/authentication"
    order="allowFirst" scope="document"
    system="https://pasta.edirepository.org">
    <allow>
      <principal>uid=JRN,o=LTER,dc=ecoinformatics,dc=org</principal>
      <permission>all</permission>
    </allow>
    <allow>
      <principal>public</principal>
      <permission>read</permission>
    </allow>
  </access>
  <dataset
      id="d210086002">
    <alternateIdentifier
        system="https://doi.org">doi:10.6073/pasta/7c9e83391e3000acbb86503925385713</alternateIdentifier><title>Quadrat vegetation cover data on 1m x 1m plots from the long-term Small Mammal Exclusion Study (SMES) at Jornada Basin LTER, 1995-2020</title>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>David C</givenName>
        <surName>Lightfoot</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Jornada Basin LTER (now at Univ. of NM)</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>dlightfo@unm.edu</electronicMailAddress>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Brandon T</givenName>
        <surName>Bestelmeyer</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>USDA-ARS Jornada Experimental Range</organizationName>
      <address>
        <deliveryPoint>P.O. Box 30003; MSC 3JER New Mexico State University</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Las Cruces</city>
        <administrativeArea>NM</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>88003-8003</postalCode>
        <country>U.S.A.</country>
      </address>
      <userId
        directory="ORCID">0000-0001-5060-9955</userId>
    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
      <organizationName>Jornada Basin LTER/New Mexico State University</organizationName>
      <positionName>Jornada Basin LTER program</positionName>
      <address>
        <deliveryPoint>P.O. Box 30003; MSC 3JER New Mexico State University</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Las Cruces</city>
        <administrativeArea>NM</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>88003-8003</postalCode>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
      <electronicMailAddress>jornada.lter@nmsu.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <onlineUrl>https://lter.jornada.nmsu.edu</onlineUrl>
    </metadataProvider>
    <pubDate>2022-04-11</pubDate>
    <language>English</language>
    <abstract>
      <para>
    This data package contains vegetation cover from plots with various
    levels of herbivore exclusion on the Jornada Experimental Range
    (JER) and Chihuahuan Desert Rangeland Research Center (CDRRC) in
    Dona Ana County, southern New Mexico, USA. Study sites were
    established in 1995; one in black grama grassland and the other in
    creosotebush shrubland to compare the impact of herbivores on
    ecosystem processes between these vegetation types. Parallel studies
    were established at the Sevilleta LTER site (New Mexico, USA) and
    Mapimi Biosphere Reserve (Durango, Mexico). Each study site is 1 km
    by 0.5 km in area. Four replicate experimental blocks were randomly
    located at the grassland study site to measure vegetation responses
    using exclusion treatments including a) all mammalian herbivores,
    including cattle, lagomorphs, and rodents, b) lagomorphs and cattle
    only, c) cattle only, and d) control accessible to all herbivores.
    Because grazing cattle are excluded from the entire creosote site,
    only three replicate experimental blocks were randomly located there
    including a) all mammalian herbivores, including lagomorphs, and
    rodents, b) lagomorphs only, and c) control accessible to all
    herbivores. Thirty-six sampling points were positioned at 5.8-meter
    intervals on a systematically located 6 by 6 point grid within each
    plot. A permanent one-meter by one-meter vegetation measurement
    quadrat is located at each of the 36 points. At each quadrat,
    percent cover by individual plant species is measured. Other
    measurements include height (cm) of each species in the quadrat, and
    plant condition (living or dead). Data were collected in the spring
    and fall of every year from 1995 to 2005. After 2005, sampling
    frequency changed to every 5 years in the fall. This study is
    ongoing.
  </para>
    </abstract>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">land use and land cover change</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">populations</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>LTER Core Research Areas</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">abundance</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">biodiversity</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">consumers</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">deserts</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">grasslands</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">herbivory</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">land cover</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">long term</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">long term monitoring</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">plant communities</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">plant cover</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">plant species</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">populations</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">shrubs</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">small mammals</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">species diversity</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">species list</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">transects</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">vegetation dynamics</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>LTER Controlled Vocabulary v1</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">ongoing</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">quadrat</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>none</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">Plant-Animal Interactions</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">Vegetation Dynamics</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">ongoing</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>Jornada Basin LTER dataset keywords</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">SMES</keyword>
      <keyword
        keywordType="theme">study 086</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>Jornada Basin project names</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
        keywordType="place">SMES</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>Jornada Basin place names</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword
          keywordType="theme">grazing</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>USDA National Ag Library's Agricultural Thesaurus</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <intellectualRights>
      <para>
  This information is released under the Creative Commons license - Attribution - CC BY 
  (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). The consumer of these data ("Data User" 
  herein) is required to cite it appropriately in any publication that results from its 
  use. The Data User should realize that these data may be actively used by others for 
  ongoing research and that coordination may be necessary to prevent duplicate 
  publication. The Data User is urged to contact the authors of these data if any 
  questions about methodology or results occur. Where appropriate, the Data User is 
  encouraged to consider collaboration or co-authorship with the authors. The Data User 
  should realize that misinterpretation of data may occur if used out of context of the 
  original study. While substantial efforts are made to ensure the accuracy of data and 
  associated documentation, complete accuracy of data sets cannot be guaranteed. All data 
  are made available "as is." The Data User should be aware, however, that data are updated 
  periodically and it is the responsibility of the Data User to check for new versions of 
  the data. The data authors and the repository where these data were obtained shall not be 
  liable for damages resulting from any use or misinterpretation of the data. Thank you.
</para>
    </intellectualRights>
    <distribution>
      <online>
        <url
      function="information">https://jrn.lternet.edu</url>
      </online>
    </distribution>
    <distribution
      id="10.6073/pasta/7c9e83391e3000acbb86503925385713" scope="system"
          system="https://pasta.edirepository.org"><online><url
        function="information">https://doi.org/10.6073/pasta/7c9e83391e3000acbb86503925385713</url></online></distribution><coverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Western Bajada: Study occurred in the western bajada geomorphic zone in the Jornada Basin. More precise geographic coordinates for this study may be requested from the JRN LTER Data Manager (jornada.data@nmsu.edu).</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-106.851460</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.729443</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>32.542771</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>32.467228</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Basin Floor: Study occurred in the basin floor geomorphic zone in the Jornada Basin. More precise geographic coordinates for this study may be requested from the JRN LTER Data Manager (jornada.data@nmsu.edu).</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-106.872883</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.692716</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>32.749487</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>32.473173</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <temporalCoverage>
        <rangeOfDates>
          <beginDate>
            <calendarDate>1995-04-03</calendarDate>
          </beginDate>
          <endDate>
            <calendarDate>2020-08-11</calendarDate>
          </endDate>
        </rangeOfDates>
      </temporalCoverage>
    </coverage>
    <maintenance>
      <description>ongoing - These data were collected yearly from 1995-2005 and every five years thereafter</description>
      <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>asNeeded</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
    </maintenance>
    <contact>
      <organizationName>Jornada Basin LTER/New Mexico State University</organizationName>
      <positionName>Jornada Basin LTER Information Manager</positionName>
      <address>
        <deliveryPoint>P.O. Box 30003, MSC 3JER New Mexico State University</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Las Cruces</city>
        <administrativeArea>NM</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>88003-8003</postalCode>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
      <phone>575-646-1739</phone>
      <electronicMailAddress>jornada.data@nmsu.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <onlineUrl>https://lter.jornada.nmsu.edu/information-management/</onlineUrl>
    </contact>
    
    <publisher><organizationName>Environmental Data Initiative</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>info@environmentaldatainitiative.org</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://environmentaldatainitiative.org</onlineUrl><userId
          directory="https://ror.org">0330j0z60</userId></publisher><pubPlace>Environmental Data Initiative</pubPlace><methods>
      <methodStep>
        <description>
          <para>
    Each study site is 1 km by 0.5 km in area. Four replicate
    experimental blocks were randomly located at each study site
    depending on whether the site was grazed. The blocks are all
    oriented on a site in an X/Y coordinate system, with the access road
    to each site forming the X axis. The compass orientation at the
    Jornada grassland site is to the north, and Jornada creosotebush
    site is oriented to the south. Treatments within each block include
    one unfenced control plot (Treatment: C; control); one plot fenced
    with barbed wire, hardware cloth, and poultry wire to exclude
    rodents, rabbits, and cattle (Treatment: R; rodent); one plot fenced
    only with barbed and poultry wire to exclude cattle and rabbits
    (Treatment: L; lagomorph); and one plot fenced with barbed wire to
    exclude cattle (Treatment B; bovine). Cattle exclosure plots with
    barbed wire occur only at the black grama grassland site where
    cattle were present, for a total of 4 treatment plots at each of the
    four grassland site blocks. There are only 3 treatment plots at each
    of the creosotebush site blocks because grazing is excluded from the
    entire creosotebush site. The treatments were randomly assigned to
    each of the three or four possible plots in each block
    independently, and their arrangements differ from block to block.
    Each of the plots in a replicate block is separated by 20 meters.
    Each plot measures 36 meters by 36 meters. Thirty-six sampling
    points are positioned at 5.8-meter intervals on a systematically
    located 6 by 6 point grid within each plot. A permanent one-meter by
    one-meter vegetation measurement quadrat is located at each of the
    36 points. All cover values are measured from a vegetation
    measurement frame placed over the quadrat, which is 1 meter by 1
    meter, and partitioned into a grid of 100, 10 cm by 10 cm squares.
  </para>
          <para>
    Fraction of canopy cover for each species present was recorded in
    increments of 0.1, to a maximum of 1.0 for each square in the
    quadrat frame. Maximum height (cm) was also recorded, by species,
    for each square. For plants, total canopy cover is measured by
    summing fractional covers, by species, for all 100 10x10 squares in
    the quadrat. Total cover values range from 0.1 to 100%. For total
    cover values less than 5%, increments of 1% were used. For cover
    values greater than 5%, estimates were made to the nearest 5%. For
    live plants, the maximum height in centimeters for that plant
    species in the quadrat is also recorded. For annuals, the highest
    part of the plant, whether it is a reproductive structure or
    vegetative structure was used. For perennials, including perennial
    grasses, the highest vegetative structure and NOT any reproductive
    structures were used. The height for bare branches is from the
    ground to the highest point if the bare branch is the highest point
    for the species. If a plant is dead, but still rooted in the soil,
    it is stated as "dead" in the condition column. For dead
    plants cover only (not height) was measured.
  </para>
          <para>
    From 1995 to 2005, vegetation data for all quadrats was measured
    twice a year in the spring and fall. After 2005, sampling frequency
    changed to once every 5 years in the fall. This study is ongoing.
  </para>
          <para>
    Field observations were recorded on micro-cassette tape recorders.
    Further details on measurements and data preparation can be found in
    the SMES vegetation quadrat protocol included with this package
    ("SMESvegquadprotocol.pdf"). A comment history is found in
    the file
    "Jornada_086_small_mammal_exclosure_quad_his.txt".
  </para>
        </description>
      </methodStep>
    </methods>
    <project>
      <title>Jornada Basin LTER</title>
      <personnel>
        <individualName>
          <salutation>Dr.</salutation>
          <givenName>Niall</givenName>
          <surName>Hanan</surName>
        </individualName>
        <address>
          <deliveryPoint>P.O. Box 30003, MSC 3JER</deliveryPoint>
          <deliveryPoint>New Mexico State University</deliveryPoint>
          <city>Las Cruces</city>
          <administrativeArea>NM</administrativeArea>
          <postalCode>88003-8003</postalCode>
          <country>United States</country>
        </address>
        <phone
      phonetype="voice">575-646-3335</phone>
        <electronicMailAddress>nhanan@nmsu.edu</electronicMailAddress>
        <role>Principal Investigator</role>
      </personnel>
      <abstract>
        <section>
          <para>The Jornada Basin Long-Term Ecological Research (LTER) program is part of a 
          national network of long-term ecological research sites funded by the US National 
          Science Foundation (NSF). The Jornada LTER program has been continuously funded
          since 1982 to develop general principles governing changes between grassland 
          and shrubland ecosystems based on long-term data collected in the Chihuahuan 
          Desert. We translate our findings to dryland ecosystems around the world, and 
          forecast the dynamics of future ecosystem states in response to changing climate 
          and land use.</para>
        </section>
      </abstract>
      <funding>
        <section>
          <para>JRN LTER is funded by the National Science Foundation under award DEB 2025166.</para>
        </section>
      </funding>
    </project>
    <dataTable
      id="68b3d5f17a23fae3ab76515aec334a21" scope="document"
          system="https://pasta.edirepository.org">
      <entityName>Quadrat percent cover table</entityName>
      <entityDescription>Vegetation cover data (percent) from 1x1 m quadrats at SMES plots</entityDescription>
      <physical>
        <objectName>JRN086002_smes_quadrat_vegcover_data.csv</objectName>
        <size
          unit="byte">9517358</size>
        <authentication
              method="MD5">da45d387b877f252d8489b93a8dcd9ba</authentication>
        <dataFormat>
          <textFormat>
            <numHeaderLines>1</numHeaderLines>
            <numFooterLines>0</numFooterLines>
            <recordDelimiter>\n</recordDelimiter>
            <attributeOrientation>column</attributeOrientation>
            <simpleDelimited>
              <fieldDelimiter>,</fieldDelimiter>
              <quoteCharacter>"</quoteCharacter>
            </simpleDelimited>
          </textFormat>
        </dataFormat>
        <distribution>
          <online>
            <url
          function="download">https://pasta.lternet.edu/package/data/eml/knb-lter-jrn/210086002/96/68b3d5f17a23fae3ab76515aec334a21</url>
          </online>
        </distribution>
      </physical>
      <attributeList>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att1">
          <attributeName>year</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Year</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Year of measurement</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>date</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <dateTime>
              <formatString>YYYY</formatString>
              <dateTimePrecision>1</dateTimePrecision>
              <dateTimeDomain/>
            </dateTime>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att2">
          <attributeName>date</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Date collected</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Date data collected</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>date</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <dateTime>
              <formatString>YYYY-MM-DD</formatString>
              <dateTimePrecision>1</dateTimePrecision>
              <dateTimeDomain/>
            </dateTime>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att3">
          <attributeName>season</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Season</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Season of data collection</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>S</code>
                    <definition>Spring</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>F</code>
                    <definition>Fall</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att4">
          <attributeName>site</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Site</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Site or location code - there are 2 SMES sites</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>G</code>
                    <definition>SMES Grassland site</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>C</code>
                    <definition>SMES Creosote site</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att5">
          <attributeName>block</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Block</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Block number</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>integer</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>1</code>
                    <definition>Block 1</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>2</code>
                    <definition>Block 2</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>3</code>
                    <definition>Block 3</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>4</code>
                    <definition>Block 4</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att6">
          <attributeName>plot</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Plot</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Plot number</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>integer</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>3</code>
                    <definition>Plot 3</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>2</code>
                    <definition>Plot 2</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>4</code>
                    <definition>Plot 4</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>1</code>
                    <definition>Plot 1</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att7">
          <attributeName>treatment</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Treatment</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Treatment type</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>R</code>
                    <definition>Rodent exclosure</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>C</code>
                    <definition>Control - no mammal exclosure</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>L</code>
                    <definition>Lagomorph exclosure</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>B</code>
                    <definition>Bovine exclosure</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att8">
          <attributeName>quad</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Quad number</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Quad number [1-36]</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>integer</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <interval>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>number</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>integer</numberType>
              </numericDomain>
            </interval>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att9">
          <attributeName>LTER_code</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>LTER plant code</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Local plant species code (Jornada LTER)</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <textDomain>
                  <definition>any text</definition>
                </textDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att10">
          <attributeName>USDA_code</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>USDA Plants code</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>USDA Plants database species code (plants.usda.gov)</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <textDomain>
                  <definition>any text</definition>
                </textDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>Missing value - data not collected or otherwise unavailable</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att11">
          <attributeName>live_dead</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Live/Dead status</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Live or dead vegetation</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>dead</code>
                    <definition>Organism(s) dead at time of observation</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>live</code>
                    <definition>Organism(s) alive at time of observation</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att12">
          <attributeName>Species_binomial</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Species binomial name</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Binomial name [Genus and species - plants.usda.gov]</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <textDomain>
                  <definition>any text</definition>
                </textDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att13">
          <attributeName>cover</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Percent cover</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Cover (%) [sum from all 10cm squares]</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>Dead plant, no height measurement taken			</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att14">
          <attributeName>height</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Height</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Maximum height (cm) for species in the quadrat</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>centimeter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>Dead plant, no height measurement taken			</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
          id="d210086002-e1-att15">
          <attributeName>id</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>History file ID</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Comment history id code. A Book or Tape number where comments are logged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <textDomain>
                  <definition>any text</definition>
                </textDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
        </attribute>
        <attribute
      id="d210086002-e1-att16">
          <attributeName>comments</attributeName>
          <attributeLabel>Comments</attributeLabel>
          <attributeDefinition>Comments on observation. In history file prior to 2012, then entered in this column</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <textDomain>
                  <definition>any text</definition>
                </textDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>No comment, quality flag, or additional information available</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
      </attributeList>
      <numberOfRecords>109963</numberOfRecords>
    </dataTable>
    <otherEntity
      id="2e364eeb6e3bcd83e6cd3ab0ae774be5" scope="document"
          system="https://pasta.edirepository.org">
      <entityName>SMES quadrat protocol</entityName>
      <entityDescription>SMES veg quadrat measurement and data preparation protocol</entityDescription>
      <physical>
        <objectName>SMESvegquadprotocol.pdf</objectName>
        <size
          unit="byte">86866</size>
        <authentication
              method="MD5">c44795a6b927f9c73e93d6f830ac088b</authentication>
        <dataFormat>
          <externallyDefinedFormat>
            <formatName>PDF</formatName>
          </externallyDefinedFormat>
        </dataFormat>
        <distribution>
          <online>
            <url
      function="download">https://pasta.lternet.edu/package/data/eml/knb-lter-jrn/210086002/96/2e364eeb6e3bcd83e6cd3ab0ae774be5</url>
          </online>
        </distribution>
      </physical>
      <entityType>otherEntity</entityType>
    </otherEntity>
    <otherEntity
      id="e526791dff89dead9af01a8331f9f054" scope="document"
          system="https://pasta.edirepository.org">
      <entityName>Data collection history file</entityName>
      <entityDescription>SMES quadrat data collection comments and history</entityDescription>
      <physical>
        <objectName>JRN086_small_mammal_exclosure_quad_his.txt</objectName>
        <size
          unit="byte">742817</size>
        <authentication
              method="MD5">1b5953eb06af45c5334641e1fdde58ce</authentication>
        <dataFormat>
          <externallyDefinedFormat>
            <formatName>text/plain</formatName>
          </externallyDefinedFormat>
        </dataFormat>
        <distribution>
          <online>
            <url
          function="download">https://pasta.lternet.edu/package/data/eml/knb-lter-jrn/210086002/96/e526791dff89dead9af01a8331f9f054</url>
          </online>
        </distribution>
      </physical>
      <entityType>otherEntity</entityType>
    </otherEntity>
  </dataset>
  <additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <unitList>
        <unit
          abbreviation="cm" id="centimeter" multiplierToSI="0.01"
          name="centimeter"
          parentSI="meter">
          <description>.01 meters</description>
        </unit>
        <unit
          id="dimensionless" name="dimensionless"
          unitType="dimensionless">
          <description>a designation asserting the absence of an associated unit</description>
        </unit>
        <unit
          id="number" name="number" unitType="dimensionless">
          <description>a quantity or amount</description>
        </unit>
      </unitList>
    </metadata>
  </additionalMetadata>
</eml:eml>
